BERTRAM L. PODELL PAPERS (APAP270) 1945-1970
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Bertram L. Podell Papers 1945-1970
nam_apap270
10.2
Podell, Bertram L. (Bertram Lawrence), 1925-
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Bertram L. Podell Papers document Podell's service as a New York State Assemblymen and Congressmen from the mid-1950s through the early 1970s.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Bertram Podell initially donated his papers in a series of acquisitions to Syracuse University between 1967 and 1971. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Bertram L. Podell was born on December 7, 1925 in Brooklyn, New York. As a young adult he served in the United States Navy during World War II. After the War, he graduated from St. John’s University in 1947 and acquired a degree in law from Brooklyn Law School in 1950. He maintained a law practice throughout his life.
A Democrat, Podell became a member of the New York State Assembly representing Kings County in 1955 and served 14 years in the 170th through 177th New York State Legislatures. In 1968 constituents elected him to the U.S. House of Representatives in a special election for the 13th Congressional District (Brooklyn). He was re-elected to Congress three more times and served until 1975. Podell was an unsuccessful candidate for re-nomination by his party in 1974.
Toward the end of his Congressional career, Podell was indicted and ultimately plead guilty to bribery charges. He served several months in jail and then returned to his law firm where he spent the remainder of his years. Podell died of kidney failure at the age of 79 on August 25, 2005 in New York.
Scope and Content Information
The Bertram L. Podell Papers document his work as a New York State Assemblyman and Congressmen during the years 1953-1970. The papers include legislative bills and files, newspapers, correspondence, resolutions, and various published materials. major topics in the subject files include conservation, education, highways, motor vehicles, labor, and gambling. A large portion of Podell's Assembly files discuss the Committee of Local Finance which he chaired for a period of time.
Overall the collection contains more material from Podell's tenure in the New York Assembly rather than the U.S. House of Representatives. Please note that the collection does not include records related to his final years in Congress, his trial or the later part of his life.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - General Subject Files, 1945-1968, Undated
Series 2 - Congressional Subject Files, 1963-1970, Undated
Series 3 - Bills and Resolutions, 1963-1967, Undated
The files in all three series are arranged alphabetically. Series 3 is arranged alphabetically by legislation type and then chronologically by bill number.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Podell, Bertram L. (Bertram Lawrence), 1925-; New York (State)--Legislature--Assembly; United States--Congress--House; Naval Applied Science Laboratory (Brooklyn, N.Y.); Politicians--New York (State); Education, Higher--New York (State); New York (State)--Politics and government; Correspondence; Legislative records; Clippings (Information Artifacts); Files by Subject
Container List
- General Subject Files, 1945-1968; Undated; 1; 6.0
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains subject files from Bertram Podell's tenure in the New York State Assembly. The files cover a wide assortment of topics, including committee work, conservation, City University, education, New York State revenue, and gambling. Correspondence and news clippings are kept within the subject files.
  - Abortion, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Air Pollution, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Assembly Calendar of Bills, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Assigned Risk-Insurance Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Automation, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Balfour Declaration 50th Anniversary, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Banking, 1967; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Banking Bill Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Banks, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Barnett, Philip, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bartlett, Richard, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Beatnicks Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Billboards Press Releases, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Birch, 1963; 1966; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Birch Society, 1966; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Birch Society Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Blue Cross, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - B'nai B'rith, 1955-1956; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board of Examiners Bill, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bonds (NYC) Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brownstein Bill on Beauty Salons, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Budget (Governor's), 1961; 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 25-27)
  - Budget Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Budget Statement, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Budgets for Select New York State Cities and Towns, 1964 (Flat-file 1)
  - Burns, John J., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Campaign (Offers of Assistance), 1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Capital City News Bureau, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Capital Punishment, 1957; 1963-1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 33-35)
  - Capital Punishment Abolishment, 1963-1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Censorship, 1962-1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Certiorari, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - City Club, 1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - City Teachers Association, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - City University and State University, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - City University Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - City University Statement (Brooklyn College Rally), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - City University Statement (JLC Meeting on Higher Education), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Civil Liberties, 1956; 1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Civil Service Employees Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Commencement Address (New York Academy of Medicine), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Mortgages and Real Estate, 1950; 1960-1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Committee to Reduce Fire Hazards (Fireman Bill), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Condolence Letters, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Condon-Waldon Law, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Confessions Amendment Press Release, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Confessions Amendment Remarks, 1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Confessions Amendment Statements, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1954; 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Constitutional Convention Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Consumer Price Index, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Cornwall Project, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Corporation Laws, 1964; 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cost of Living, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Cost of Living Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Crime Compensation Act, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Crime Rate (Growing), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Crisis (New York City), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dairymen's League, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Democratic Legislative Program, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Democratic Program, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Divorce Law, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Education, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Education (Joint Legislative Committee), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Education (Public), 1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Election Law, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Electronic Voting, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Ellenbogen, Seymour, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ethics, 1964-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Eulogies, 1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Favor File, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Feedback, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Finances (New York State), 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Finances (State), 1963-1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Fiscal Affairs (New York City), 1956; 1960; 1962-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 44-46)
  - Fiscal Program Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Fiscal Reports (New York City), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Fiscal Resources (Haller Plan), 1964-1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Fisher, Albert W., 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Flatbush Democratic Club, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Flatbush Library Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Food Packaging and Marketing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Form Letters, 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Fox, J. Lewis, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Froehlich, David, 1964-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Full Crew Law, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Gilbert, Hugh, Undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Gimma, Joseph A., 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Goldwater and Flynn, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Governor's Releases, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Governor's Transportation Bond Issue, 1967; Undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Grundstein, Amrant S., Undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hanna, Edward A., 1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Harlem Cultural Center, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Higher Education (Folder 1 of 2), 1957; 1960-1967; Undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Higher Education (Folder 2 of 2), 1957; 1960-1967; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Higher Education Statement (At Public Housing), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Higher Education Statement (City University Students), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Highway Safety, 1964; 1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hospitals, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hospital Resolution Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Housing, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Housing Program Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Humane Slaughter, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hypnosis, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Income Pay (Correspondence), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Infant Mortality (Correspondence), 1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Infant Mortality Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Integration (Schools), 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Investing in New York City Real Estate, 1953; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Investments (State), 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Job Development Authority, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Joint Legislative Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Higher Education, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on State Fiscal Policies, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Joint Legislative Committee to Study Revisions of Corporate Laws, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 21-23)
  - Judges Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Katzman, Barry, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Kerr-Mills Law, 1960; 1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Kisburg, Nicholas, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Leadership Fight, 1965; Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Legislation (Misc. Correspondence), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
  - Legislation (Misc. Correspondence), 1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
  - Legislative Hearing, 1967; Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Legislative Manuel Requests, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Legislative Memorandum, 1963-1965; Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Legislative Reform, 1962; Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Lexington School for the Deaf, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Liberal Party, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Libraries Press Releases (New York City), 1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Library Bill, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lieberman, Mark, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Lindsay Administration Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Lindsay, John, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Lobbyists, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lobbyists, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Lobbyists, 1967; Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Local Finance (Marsh Public Health), 1966-1967; Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Local Finance Committee, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Local Finance Law, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Local Finance Measures, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Local Finance Resolutions, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Local Finance Resolutions, 1966; Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Local Government, 1959; 1965-1966; Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Local Government, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Local Government Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Local Government Press Releases, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Local Government Statements, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Local Government Toronto, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Local School Boards, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Long Island University, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Lottery, 1964-1965; 1967 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Luddy, William (Chairman of the Westchester Democratic Committee), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Mangano-Ferrall Bill (Textbooks), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Mattice, Frances J., Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Medicaid, 1967; Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Medicare, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Medicare Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Memos to Members From B.L. Podell, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Message of Necessity Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Message of Necessity Statement, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Milk Control, 1960; 1963-1964; Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Milk Program Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Minimum Wage, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966; Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Modlin, Vivian, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Morse, James, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Mortgage Leases Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Muraski, Gloria, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Narcotics, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Narcotics Press Releases, 1967; Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Nash, Thomas (Chauffeur), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - National Maritime Union of America, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - New York Airways, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - New York State Job Development Authority, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Newsletters, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Nickerson, Eugene H., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - No-Sock Bill, 1955; 1965 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Noble, Paul (WNEW-TV Ch. 5), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Nurses, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Nurses' Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Nurses' Salaries Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Obscene Literature, 1963; 1965; Undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Off-Track Betting, 1959; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Off-Track Betting (In Favor of Off-Track Betting), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Off-Track Betting (Oppose Off-Track Betting), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Orin Lehman, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Palestine Resolution, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Parker, John, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Past Legislative Sessions, 1956; 1958-1960; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Penal Law and Criminal Law, 1965; 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Per Capita Aid, 1949-1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Personal (Podell), 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Platform, 1962; 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Podell and Podell, ESQS, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Prayers, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Press Conference, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Primary (State-Wide), 1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Programs and Platforms, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Prospect Park Centennial Days, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Public Health, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Public Hearings, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Publications (Official List), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Racial Problems, 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Racing Legislation, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Railroads, 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Real Estate Mortgages, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Real Estate Tax, 1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Reapportionment, 1960; 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Reapportionment, 1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Red Books and Manuals, 1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Regional Planning, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Religion and the Schools, 1955-1956; 1961; Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Resolution 131: Local Finance Committee to Study Local Government, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Retail Merchants (Cliff Alanson), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Rockefeller, 1964; 1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Rockefeller Railroad Improvements, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Rockefeller Resolution, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Rosen, Richard M., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Sabbath Bill, 1955; 1958-1959; 1962-1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Sabbatical Leave, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Save the MET, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Scholarship Letters, Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Scholarship Letters, Undated (Flat-file 2)
  - Scholarship Winners, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Science Technology Foundation, 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Sewage Bill, 1967; Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Single Letting, 1945; 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Single Letting, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Slums in the City (Press Releases), Undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Speaker of the Assembly (Notices), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Speeches, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - St. John's University, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Staff-J.L.C., Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Standing Committees, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - State Platform, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Statistical Spreadsheets and Addresses, 1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Steingut Program, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Stenographic Services, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Summary of Bills, Undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Summer Jobs, 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Surety Bonds Press Releases, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Tax Program, 1961-1962; 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Taxation (New York City), 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Taxation (New York State), 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Teacher Pensions (Correspondence), 1966; Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Teacher Retirement Bill, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Telegrams Sent, 1965; Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Television-Radio-Etc., 1965; Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Terminal Leave Pay Municipal Employees, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Textbook Bill, 1966; Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Transit, 1963; 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Transit, 1965; Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Transit Authority and Transit Workers Union, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Transit Fare Increase Press Releases, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Transportation, 1962; 1965; Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Transportation, 1965; 1967 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Travia, Anthony J. (Speaker), 1965-1966; Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority, 1964-1966; Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Twin Double, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Unanswered Correspondence (Insufficient Address), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Unanswered Letters (Out of District), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Vacationlands, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Vassar College, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Voting Age (Correspondence), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Voting Age (Press Releases), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Voting Bill-18 Years Old, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Wagner, Robert (Mayor), 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Water Commission, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Water Districts Press Releases (NYS), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Water Metering Press Releases, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Water Rates Press Releases, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Water Resources Planning, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Water Resources Planning Press Releases, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Water Resources Statements, 1966; Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Water Restrictions Press Releases, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Water Supply Board Intro 6630 Correspondence, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Weapons Legislation, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Weintraub, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - World's Fair, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Youman's, Mark R., 1966; Undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Young Democrats (New York State College), Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Congressional Subject Files, 1963-1970; Undated; 2; 3.0
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains material related to Bertram Podell's tenure in the U.S. House of Representatives. In addition to bills, files contain news clippings and correspondence. A large majority of the files in this series are related to the Naval Applied Science Laboratory located in the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
  - Ad Hoc Committee Case Study Prepared for the Secretary of the Navy, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration: Additional Copies of Kennedy Tribute, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agriculture: Elderly Exchange Food Stamps for Prepared Meals, 1969; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agriculture: Food Stamp Reform Act of 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agriculture: Human Nutrition Act of 1969, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agriculture: National Pesticide Commission Act of 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agriculture: Removal of Flaws in Food Stamp Program, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agriculture: Terminate Sugar Quota for South Africa, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agriculture Workers: National Labor Relations Act, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aid to Polish Jewry, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alternative Plan for the Naval Applied Science Laboratory, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - An Urban Problem of New York: A Test Case, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Appropriations: Supplemental Appropriations for Bilingual Education Act, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Appropriations: Supplemental Appropriations for Head Start for Fiscal 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Armed Forces: Congressional Medal of Honor to Apollo 8, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Armed Forces: Definition of Conscientious Objector, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Armed Forces: Health Care Benefits, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Armed Forces: Supreme Sacrifice Medal, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Armed Forces: To Create an Office of Defense Review, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Atomic Energy: Enrico Fermi Nuclear Accelerator, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Aviation: Airport and Airways Development Act of 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Aviation: CAB Authority in Relieving Airport Congestion, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Aviation: Civil Aircraft, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Aviation: Rate Reductions, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Aviation: Requirements for Air Traffic Controllers, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Banking: Crime Protection Insurance, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Broker Insurance Corporation, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Case for Retention of the Naval Applied Science Laboratory, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Census Question Limitation, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Civil Rights: Internal Revenue Code of 1954, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Civil Service: Postal Pay Raise, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)